

Contact

- +(40) 756 777 033
- 🕢 bogdan.bitfoi@gmail.com
- O Cluj-Napoca, Romania
- in/bogdan-bitfoi
- s bogdan.bitfoi

Skills

Java	5 years
SQL	5 years
Spring	5 years
Hibernate	5 years
REST APIs	5 years
Docker	4 years
Kubernetes	1 year
Python	1 year
.NET	1 year

Education

Babes-Bolyai University Master's Degree in Software Engineering Cluj Napoca, 2015-2017

Babes-Bolyai UniversityBachelor's Degree in Software Engineering
Cluj Napoca, 2012-2015

BOGDAN BÎTFOI

Senior JAVA Developer • Contractor • Freelancer

About me

I am a consultant / contractor / freelancer with 5+ years of experience, only interested in remote work.

I help companies around the world to design and implement their software solutions.

Drop me a message if you think my expertise could help your organization!

Work Experience

Senior Java Developer

Aera Technology

06/2019 - Present

Romania

The client, owner of a supply-chain automation software, was dealing with declining trust in front of customers and implicitly a huge drop in revenue due to various software malfunctions and poorly managed workflows in the solution provided to the end client.

- Assured the renewal of 4 important contracts worth over \$5M, by being in constant close communication with customers' representatives in order to create a branching mechanism where users can work on the same processes.
- Ensured 100% more efficient communication by reducing development time for other teams, by providing an elegant, straightforward channel, which allowed other teams to integrate their areas of the project within the branching solution.

Skills: Java 8, Spring Boot, AWS (S3), MySQL, TestNG, Mockito, Git, Gradle.

Senior Java Developer

msg Systems (Intelligent Reinsurance)

01/2018 - 05/2019

Romani

The client, a Software developer for the Insurance Market, was looking to provide a solution to small-to-medium Insurance/Reinsurance companies for automation of processes within the management of insurance policies, due to the lack of an automated software solution.

- Earned an estimated €1.5M for the client by designing and building the automated software solution, by providing several microservices managing areas such as risk calculation and invoice splitting amongst the network of reinsurers.
- Increased productivity in the development process by more than 2x, by being heavily involved in the training of the other team members, both technical and business-related, by using pair programming techniques.

Skills: Java 8, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Microservices, Git, Javascript, Postgres.

Senior Java Developer

Hewlett Packard Enterprise (Data Center Automation)

06/2016 - 12/2017

The client, a Software developer in the server-side automation, was aiming to secure new contracts by solving the general problem of time inefficiency within the IT/DevOps department in companies but was lacking the implementation of the already existent architecture.

- Reduced more than 40% of operational costs and reduced time needed to install OS updates
 from 1 month to under a day by completely automating the whole system by providing REST API's
 which connected to the OS' companies to download and store the errata and erratums and install
 them on specific computers within the client's network
- Secured more than 5 multi-million dollar yearly contracts with huge corporations throughout
 the world that continue to this day by providing a versatile solution, compatible with a large variety
 of operating systems such as Microsoft, Apple's Mac OS, SuSE, RHEL.

Skills: Java 8, Python, .NET, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Shell Scripting, Postgres, Docker, Kubernetes.